This neural tube will divide into two main parts, the brain and the spinal region.
この神経管は、脳と脊髄の2つの主要な部分に分かれます。
spinal.
脊髄領域。
There is first a first closure, it is really linked to this force of the heart.
まず最初の閉鎖があり、これは心臓の力と本当に関連しています。
And then it will be done a bit like a zipper, from the bottom up.
そして、それはジッパーのように、下から上へと少しずつ行われます。
up.
上へ。
But not like a zipper, it can do a little here, and
しかし、ジッパーのようにではなく、まさにそれが少しここで、そして
there still a little open, then close it.
まだ少し開いていて、それから閉じる。
So we are there, it will do like this, it will do like this.
だから私たちはそこにいて、それはこのように、このようにするでしょう。
We will study.
私たちは勉強します。
the dynamics of brain development, of neurons,
脳、ニューロン、グリア細胞、大量の血液の発生のダイナミクス。
of glial cells, a lot of blood.
グリア細胞、大量の血液。
You have a large supply of oxygen and glucose, but
あなたは大量の酸素とブドウ糖の供給を受けていますが、
you also have very important drainage areas.
非常に重要な排水ゾーンもあります。
This is the cerebrospinal fluid system.
これは脳脊髄液システムです。
The cephalic neural tube, we see that at the beginning, we already have a first image
頭部神経管は、最初からすでにこの神経管の最初の画像があることがわかります。
of this neural tube.
この神経管の。
It's the neural plate.
それは神経板です。
notochord and so it is the notochord again which is the inducing force for the whole tube.
脊索、そしてそれは再び脊索であり、管全体の誘導力です。
But also we see that there is, by the shape that the embryo takes, it
しかし、胚が取る形によって、それが
takes the shape a little
少しラケットのような形をしています。
of a racket. So there is a part here where I have an
ラケットのような形をしています。だから、ここに私が持っている部分があります。
important feeding zone which makes
重要な栄養ゾーンがあり、それが
that the part here of the cranial part of the brain develops. From the moment
脳の頭蓋部分が発達します。その瞬間から
where
どこで
It is maintained by the anterior part of
それは前方の血管部分によって維持されています。
vascular type, you see.
血管タイプ、ほら。
It comes to wrap around the front.
それは前方に巻き付きます。
It comes to put the heart which becomes a fulcrum, it comes to wrap around.
それは心臓を支点として置き、それが巻き付きます。
It will form, you see, small vesicles like that.
それは、ほら、このように小さな小胞を形成します。
So the ascent of the neural tube will produce here
したがって、神経管の上昇は、ここに小胞を生成します。
vesicles.
小胞。
These vesicles wrap around a fulcrum.
これらの小胞は支点に巻き付きます。
which are found at the level of the heart and at the level of the cardio cavity
心臓と心臓腹膜腔のレベルで見られます。
-peritoneal.
-腹膜。
We could say that it is almost a joint for the developing nervous system.
それは発達中の神経系にとってほとんど関節であると言えるでしょう。
At the same time, we see here that there is still a guide behind
同時に、ここにはまだ後ろにガイドがあることがわかります。
which is all around
それは周り全体にあります。
which is called the amniotic cavity, which completely reorganizes the
羊膜腔と呼ばれるもので、胚を完全に再編成します。
embryo
胚を
towards a fulcrum which is the embryonic pedicle.
胚柄である支点に向かって。
The embryo that comes to wrap around...
胚が巻き付いていきます...
around, completely, completely, the cardio cavity
完全に、完全に、心臓の空洞の周りに
-pleuro-peritoneal.
-胸膜-腹膜。
The growth is enormous.
成長は計り知れません。
We see that there is a very important development here, already, which begins of all
ここには非常に重要な発達があり、すでに全体が始まっていることがわかります。
the part, which restarts another development here, and then there is a kind of succession
その部分が、ここで別の発達を再開させ、そして一種の連続があります。
between a growth movement, a movement, here, you see, each
成長の動きと、ここでの動きの間には、常に
time of ascent
上昇の
of growth here.
ここでの成長。
And we will see the movement that descends to growth through here, at
そして、成長に向かって下降する動きを、ここから見ていきます。
the same time that it
同時に、それが
happens here, you see, each time the wrapping.
ここで起こっている、ほら、毎回巻き付いている。
And we, we will now begin little by little to study in detail what happens
そして私たちは今、何が起こっているのかを少しずつ詳細に研究し始めます。
Because not only are there a lot of things happening at the level of the brain, of the base
なぜなら、脳、脳底、
of the brain, of the viscerocranium and of the whole system that is here, because all this will
脳底、内臓頭蓋、そしてここにあるシステム全体で多くのことが起こっているだけでなく、これらすべてが
be interdependent of our system.
私たちのシステムと相互依存するからです。
we will try to simplify
私たちは単純化しようとします
and we will take as a reference point
そして、私たちは参照点として
the developmental movement of the brain
脳の発達運動を
from the structure
構造から
mesoblastic
中胚葉の
that is to say from the cartilaginous structure
つまり、軟骨構造から
of the base of the skull
頭蓋底の
we will also add all the movement
私たちはまた、すべての動きを追加します
of ventricle development
脳室の発達の
okay
はい
and again
そして再び
above we will add
その上に、私たちは追加します
all the meninges
すべての髄膜を
all the meningeal organization
髄膜の組織全体を
And we will see that at a given moment, the embryo will make a movement of flexion and
そして、ある時点で、胚が屈曲と
straightening.
伸展の動きをすることを見るでしょう。
And we will try to understand why this straightening happens and what are the practical implications.
そして、なぜこの伸展が起こるのか、そしてその実践的な
practical.
意味合いは何なのかを理解しようとします。
What are the implications in its morphogenesis, in its morphology that will be involved.
その形態形成、その形態にどのような意味合いがあるのか、それが関与するでしょう。
And then we're going to play, we're going to work with the brain, we're going to take the brain.
そして、私たちは脳で遊び、脳を扱います。
And you will see that I call it the unfolding of the nervous system.
そして、私がこれを神経系の展開と呼んでいることがわかるでしょう。
It's very pleasant and it's a great therapeutic tool.
それは非常に快適で、素晴らしい治療ツールです。
It's so powerful it will help you.
それは非常に強力なので、あなたを助けるでしょう。
At the same time that I have this development of my neural tube,
私の神経管が発達しているのと同時に、
there is all the implication of the delimitation of the embryo that is taking place.
胚の境界が形成されることの全体的な関与があります。
It will happen synchronously.
それは同期的に行われます。
We will especially focus on that now.
私たちは今、特にそれに焦点を当てます。
And we will add around it each time, from these movements.
そして、これらの動きから、毎回その周りに付け加えていきます。
Do you understand the idea?
アイデアは分かりますか？
Since we have a nice specific developmental pattern,
特定の素晴らしい発達パターンがあるので、
with still some flexions, some things like that that will appear,
いくつかの屈曲や、そのようなものが現れるでしょうが、
we will see again that at the moment what happens below,
下で起こっていることが、
it will happen at the same time as certain things, you see.
特定の事柄と同時に起こることを再確認します。
And we will be able to have our reference.
そして、私たちは参照点を持つことができます。
Now, we will try to properly develop the brain's little tai chi.
さて、脳の小さな太極拳をうまく発展させていきましょう。
You know that this movement is essentially linked, in fact,
この動きは本質的に、実際には、
It is the vascular field that is here, linked by the movement
ここにある血管の場が、心臓の動きによって結合されており、
of the heart with simply the algorithm we saw which was
私たちが以前見たアルゴリズム、つまり
a differentiated growth rate.
分化した成長速度によって結合されています。
The brain develops, the neural tube develops very quickly, which forces the brain
脳が発達し、神経管が非常に速く発達するため、脳は
to flex forward.
前方に屈曲せざるを得ません。
This will cause what we call here cephalic type curvatures
これは、ここで頭部型湾曲と
and cervical type curvatures.
頸部型湾曲と呼ばれるものを引き起こします。
First thing I want to say is that it's a bit more complicated.
まず言いたいのは、これはもう少し複雑だということです。
that will appear, it's a kind of expansion movement.
現れるのは、一種の拡張運動です。
Secondly, it's a forward flexion movement.
第二に、それは前方への屈曲運動です。
You see, the embryo, if it's lying on the table facing the ceiling,
ほら、胚が仰向けにテーブルに横たわっていると、
the first thing it does, it grows towards me like that.
最初にすることは、このように私に向かって成長することです。
I have an expansion.
拡張があります。
Secondly, by the differential growth rate,
第二に、分化成長速度によって、
the horde in front slows down,
前方の群れが減速し、
and the embryo makes a forward flexion movement.
胚は前方への屈曲運動をします。
It bends here.
ここで曲がります。
And we see a flexion appearing here.
そして、ここに屈曲が現れます。
flexion that will appear here, the cervical flexion and the cephalic flexion, you
ここに現れる屈曲、頸部屈曲と頭部屈曲、
see
ほら、
that it starts to do that, the flexion continues here, it continues and
それがこのように始まり、屈曲はここで続き、そして
at a given moment the brain
ある時点で脳は
here in its development, it comes on the heart, it
その発達において、心臓の上に乗り、
comes on the heart and behind here
心臓の上に乗り、そしてその背後で
the neural tube continues to grow, so I have a brake here that is created, you
神経管は成長し続けるので、ここにブレーキがかかり、
see, and
ほら、そして
I have a posterior thrust there.
後方からの推進力があります。
that continue in growth.
それが成長を続けています。
This posterior thrust creates an angle above, here,
この後方への押し出しが、ここで上方に角度を作り出します。
which we will call the pontine curvature.
これを橋脳曲と呼びます。
This pontine curvature, at some point,
この橋脳曲は、ある時点で、
the system continues to grow,
システムは成長を続け、
and there, if I put it now face on,
そして、もし私が今これを正面から見ると、
at first, it looks like this,
最初はこう見えます。
and this prosencephalon will begin to form two vesicles from the front.
そしてこの前脳は、正面から2つの小胞を形成し始めます。
this, you see, what we call the bulges of the
これ、見てください、いわゆる脳の膨らみです。
telencephalon. I repeat, I
脳。繰り返します、
have an ascent of
私の管の上昇があり、
my tube, I have flexion and we see a cephalic flexion appear. It
屈曲があり、頭部屈曲が現れるのが見えます。これは
continues, at the same time
同時に続きます。
in this cephalic flexion I have a cervical flexion. The tube continues to push
この頭部屈曲の中に頸部屈曲があります。管は後ろに押し出され続けます。
behind,
後ろに、
you see here, it meets...
ここを見てください、それは出会います...
heart and there is an appearance that we call the pontine flexion that appears,
心臓、そしてそこに橋脳屈曲と呼ばれるものが出現します。
it
それは
continues to grow and there we see at that moment what we call the
成長を続け、その時点で、いわゆる
process
終脳化のプロセスが現れるのが見えます。この終脳化のプロセスは、
of telencephalization, this process of telencephalization goes
ある時点で後ろに向かって
at a given moment backwards
このように進みます。だから、この動きがあります。私の
like this, so I have this movement, I see my
小さな胚がここで成長しているのが見えます。屈曲、
little embryo growing here, flexion
頭部屈曲、頸部屈曲、橋脳屈曲、
Cephalic flexion, cervical flexion, pontine flexion,
終脳化が発達し、私の胚の完全な発達に到達します。
telencephalization that develops to reach a complete development
私の胚の。
of my embryo.
神経管は、まず前脳、次に中脳、そして菱脳であることがわかります。
Neural tube, we see that it is first the prosencephalon, then the
中脳、そして菱脳。
mesencephalon, then the rhombencephalon.
前脳は終脳と間脳になります。
The prosencephalon will become the telencephalon and the diencephalon.
そして、そこに間脳が見えます。
and there we see the diencephalon.
次に、ここに構造が見えます。
Then we see here the structure
それは中脳の構造でした。
which was the mesencephalic structure
それがここにある中脳になります。
which will become the mesencephalon here.
そして、後方の構造もまた、
And then the posterior structure too
もしよろしければ、
which will form, if you like,
髄脳を形成します。
the myelencephalon,
ここに、
here, there,
そして後脳を。
and the metencephalon.
私たちは特にこのダイナミクスに注目します。
We will especially focus our attention
このダイナミクスに注目します。
Because that's the key we need to find.
なぜなら、それが私たちが見つけなければならない鍵だからです。
This key here.
ここにあるこの鍵。
At that moment, already, the heart, we are already, at this stage,
その時、すでに心臓は、この段階で、
we are already around the 23rd day, 23rd, 24th day.
すでに23日目、23日目、24日目頃です。
That means that at that moment, the heart is already beating very strongly.
つまり、その時、心臓はすでに力強く鼓動しています。
So already, in the brain, what can I see in its development phase?
では、脳の発達段階で何が見えるでしょうか？
At the beginning, it's a, it's just
最初は、それはただの
a disk.
円盤です。
2 it becomes a groove, 3 it becomes a groove that begins to close,
2つ目は溝になり、3つ目は閉じ始める溝になり、
4 it begins to expand very strongly at the cephalic level,
4つ目は頭部で非常に強く膨張し始め、
then it makes a forward flexion movement, there, at the same time it
そして前方に屈曲運動を起こし、同時に
makes a cervical flexion movement,
頸部屈曲運動を起こし、
I reach a point, it continues to grow, and there it makes a posterior fold at the rhombencephalic level
ある点に達し、成長を続け、そこで菱脳レベルで後方への折り返しが起こり、
to form the pontine curvature, you see,
橋の湾曲を形成します、分かりますか？
and then...
そして...
behind the telencephalon itself begins to open, it pushes but there it no longer has
その後、終脳は開き始め、押し出されますが、そこにはもう
space to go
進むためのスペースがなく、
forward and what does it do, it goes back and we will see that. The
どうなるかというと、後方に戻ります。これについては後で説明します。
three encephalons,
3つの脳、
mesencephalon, rhombencephalon and the spinal canal.
中脳、菱脳、そして脊髄管。
This rhombencephalon grows and there are two of them
この菱脳は成長し、両側に2つずつあり、両方とも成長し始めます。
on each side and it starts to grow from both.
側方に、そしてある時点で、心臓を介して、最初に発達するシステムを介して、そしてまた化学的な集中を介して、前方にブレーキがかかります。そしてそれは巨大な膨張を起こします。
it made a movement like this but there it can no longer go
それはこのような動きをしていましたが、もうそこには行けません。
that way and all
そこには行けません。
of a sudden what happens is that posteriorly I reach a state of
突然、何が起こるかというと、後方で平衡状態に達します。つまり、もう屈曲できないということです。
because I have reached a state of equilibrium
平衡状態に達したからです。
posterior on a hydrodynamic plane
流体力学的な観点から後方で、
that I will start now
今から始めます。
all of a sudden
突然、
the vesicle, what does it do?
小胞は何をするでしょうか？
It starts to do that.
それはこれをし始めます。
I grow.
私は成長します。
What do I become?
私は何になるのでしょうか？
I become my hemispheres.
私は自分の半球になります。
He leaves.
それは出発します。
and begins to make this dynamic movement
そして、このダイナミックな動きを始めます。
and we
そして、私たちは
see here
ここで
really the pattern, almost the path
本当にパターン、ほとんど軌跡を見ます。
of its development here
ここでのその発達の
an H-point
H点
with a fulcrum
支点とともに
with a reference point
参照点とともに
for this rotation
この回転のために
already what we will call
すでに私たちが呼ぶもの
in the structure now called
今私たちが呼ぶ構造の中で
the insula
島皮質
they are hard
それらは硬いです
of place the cervical flexion and the flexion an adaptation to
頸部屈曲と屈曲を配置することは、環境への適応です。
the environment because
なぜなら、このストッパーがあるからです。ある時点で、私は本当にこの成長をしています。
there is this stop that at one point, there, I really have this growth at
前方へ、わかりますか？
the front, you see
そして、ここで何が見えるかというと、それは成長し続けています。今、ここに私はブレーキを持っています。
and there what we see is that it continues to grow now here I
私自身はここにいますが、同時に起こっていることは、ここの脳は、わかりますか、非常によく知っているということです。
have a brake
その
here but at the same time what happens is that the brain here you see knows very well
それはここでリズミカルな情報を受け取ります。
the
そして、それは発達します。
It receives rhythmic information here.
私は欲求があり、空腹で、食べます。
Then, it develops.
私は成長したい。
I want, I'm hungry, I eat.
ここで、後ろで、橋の縫合が閉じます。
I want to grow.
そこで何が形成されるのでしょうか？
Here, behind, the pontine curvature closes.
菱脳のレベルでそれは何になるのでしょうか？
What will form there?
小脳。
What will it be at the level of the rhombencephalon?
そして、それは何を与えるのでしょうか、この突出は？
The cerebellum.
待機。
And what will that curvature give?
それは神経管の上昇と心臓への支点との間のバランスです。
The tentorium.
私が好きなもう一つの画像は、それがすでに終脳のプロセスと呼ぶものの正確な分節化を可能にするからです。
It is a balance between the ascent of the neural tube and the fulcrum on the
そして、私たちが菱脳と呼ぶもののレベルでのすべての移動です。
So the rhombomeres, 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6.
つまり、菱脳節は1、2、3、4、5、6。
seven, eight, which are there.
7、8がそこにある。
And then we see here well
そして、ここでよくわかるのは
the backward development
このプロセスの
of this process.
後方への発達だ。
We go into details
私たちは詳細に入り込む
specifics that can be found.
特定のものを特定できる。
Here, we will now see
ここで、今から見るのは
again these different
この異なる
flexions of this tube
管の屈曲だ。
between the 28th and 40th
28日目から40日目の間に、
day, I have this development.
この発達がある。
Around the 8th
8週目頃、11週目と
week, between the 11th
ここ、わかるだろうか。
and here, you see,
私は思う。
I think.
私は本当にこの橋屈曲がここで明確に定義され始めているのを感じる。
I start to really have this pontine flexure that starts to be well defined here.
そしてここで、私は本当に私の終脳の発達が
And then here, I start to really have the development of my telencephalon
完全に皆の上に現れるのを感じ始める。
which comes completely above everyone else.
そして、これについて、私たちはここで再び
And on top of that, we take again here with the growth
神経管のレベルでの
important at the level of the neural tube,
重要な成長、
the mesencephalic flexion, the cervical flexion.
中脳屈曲、頸部屈曲を取り上げる。
Then we see the meeting here.
そして、ここで出会いが見られる。
which will give us the pontine flexion with the growth here and the development here.
それが橋屈曲を、ここでの成長とここでの発達とともに与える。
And then, posteriorly, we will have the whole process of telencephalization
そして、後方には、
which comes to completely wrap, with each time here, you see,
完全に包み込む終脳化の全プロセスがある。ここで、毎回、わかるだろうか。
a concentration at some point of energy that will happen here,
ある時点でエネルギーが集中し、それがここで起こる。
concentration of points, and we can also say that the balance point,
点の集中、そしてバランスの点、
the equilibrium point, the each point,
均衡の点、各点も言える。
for the development of the telencephalon,
終脳の発達のために、
we will find it at the level...
私たちはそれを...のレベルで見つけるだろう。
So we see here the insula, it's a lobe in fact.
ここで島が見えるが、それは実際には葉だ。
It's the insular lobe that's here.
ここにあるのは島葉だ。
Here we have a bit of the parameter diagram,
ここでは、パラメータの図が少しある。
you see, with the global flexion,
わかるだろうか、全体的な屈曲とともに。
and then we see all these points that will,
そして、これらすべての点が見える。
the three flexions that will.
3つの屈曲が進む。
The importance here of this movement,
この動きの重要性、
all of a sudden straightening.
突然の直立。
So there will also be certain synchronicities.
そして、いくつかの同時性も存在するだろう。
We see that the flexion...
屈曲が見られます...
cephalic, here, will be in agreement with the tip of my notochord,
脳の、ここでは、私の脊索の先端と一致します、
the fulcrum.
支持点。
The cervical flexion will be in relation to the supraocciput, while
頸椎の屈曲は後頭骨上部と関連し、一方、
the flexion
連続的な屈曲は
pontine will be in relation to the occipital base. And the telencephalic flexion
後頭骨底部と関連します。そして、
telencephalic
終脳の屈曲は
will be on the movement of my sphenoids, of my pre-sphenoids.
私の蝶形骨、前蝶形骨の動きに影響されます。
If I am my prosencephalon.
もし私が私の前脳であるならば。
I come forward, hop, I arrive, and hop, and there
私は前方に進み、ホップ、到着し、ホップ、そしてそこで
all of a sudden, I go back.
突然、私は後方に戻ります。
The celsus neurocranium or which is equal to what we call the process
脳神経頭蓋、または脳化のプロセスと呼ばれるものに等しいもの。
of cerebralization.
脳化のプロセス。
And at the same time, posteriorly, I have a change at the level of my primitive sclerotomes
そして同時に、後方では、私の原始的な硬化症に変化があり、
which reach a state of densification.
それは緻密化の状態に達します。
That is to say that I have reached...
つまり、私は到達しました...
and there, it happens at the same time
そして、それは同時に起こります
that I can start to straighten up like that.
私がこのようにまっすぐになり始めることができること。
I can leave.
私は出発できます。
At the same time, my whole system,
同時に、私のシステム全体、
what we call the anterior midline.
前正中線と呼ばれるもの。
Look what they do.
彼らが何をするか見てください。
Everything moves towards the midline.
すべてが正中線に近づきます。
By this process,
このプロセスによって、
everything that is closed here
ここに閉じ込められているすべてが
starts to come back towards the midline.
正中線に戻り始めます。
This is how this anterior midline
このようにして、この前正中線が
starts to form.
形成され始めます。
It is linked to the process of tightening.
それは締め付けるプロセスに関連しています。
and to the process of descent of the visceral system.
そして内臓系の下降プロセスに関連しています。
So I have a visceral fulcrum and I have a tension towards the other.
したがって、私は内臓の支持点と、他方への張力を持っています。
This is the first movement and we will see that in
これが最初の動きであり、この発達において、
this development,
この発達において、
afterwards we will add the base of the skull,
その後、頭蓋底を追加し、
then we will add the ventricles that will follow this development
次に、この発達に続く脳室を追加し、
and then we will add all the membranes behind.
そして後方にはすべての膜を追加します。
all the organization, all the compartment of my dura mater,
すべての組織、私の硬膜のすべての区画、
membranes, etc., falx cerebri, tentorium cerebelli, etc.
膜など、脳の欠陥、脳の腱など。
And then we will add the dural sheaths again
そして、さらに硬膜鞘を追加して、
to make the vault.
頭蓋冠を形成します。
The very first movement is an expansion.
最初の動きは拡張です。
It grows.
それは成長します。
If it doesn't grow, what could it be?
もし成長しないなら、それは何でしょうか？
A deficit?
欠損でしょうか？
vascular. Don't forget that the system here is also magnetic force, electromagnetic,
血管。システムが磁力、電磁力、
energetic. It grows, it comes towards
エネルギーでもあることを忘れないでください。それは成長し、あなたに向かって
you and it grows towards you. Does it grow? Okay. Then
来て、あなたに向かって成長します。成長していますか？はい。それから
it makes a forward flexion movement. The brain develops, it makes a movement
それは前方に屈曲運動をします。脳が発達し、それは
of
小胞の
vesicle forward, it comes towards the heart like that. But at the same time, behind,
前向きな動きをし、このように心臓に向かってきます。しかし同時に、後ろでは、
posteriorly, I have a flexion.
後方では、屈曲があります。
cephalic flexion
頭部屈曲
and behind I have a cervical flexion
そして後ろでは頸部屈曲があります
at the same time at the level of my fingers
同時に私の指のレベルでは
behind it continues to push
後ろではそれが押し続け
and there I start to have
そしてそこで私は持ち始めます
what we call the flexion
屈曲と呼ばれるもの
pontine that appears
橋の屈曲が現れます
at the level of my hands here
私の手のこのレベルで
behind I have an expansion
後ろでは私は拡張を持っています
enormous of my
私の
prosencephalon that comes
前脳の巨大な拡張が来て
and makes a whole movement
そしてそれは全体の動きをします
of
の
cerebralization
脳化
telencephalization that I recover at the occipito-temporal level.
大脳化を私は後頭
-temporal.
-側頭のレベルで回復します。